this is a day
i've been looking forward to for
two-and-a-half years
every once in awhile
a revolutionary product comes along
changes everything
apple has been
well first of all was very fortunate
if you get to work on just wannabes
in your career
apples in very fortunate
it's been able to
introduced a few of these into the world
nineteen eighty four
you choose the macintosh
villages change apple
it change the whole computer industry
in two thousand one
we choose the first pipeline
if interest
within this change the way we always the
music
it change the entire music industry
were introducing
three
revolutionary products of this class
the first one
is a widescreen high part with touches
the seconds
is a revolutionary the
and the third
is a breakthrough
internet communications device
three things
widescreen ipod with such controls
a revolutionary mobile phone
and a breakthrough internet
communications lines
an ipod
a farm
an internet communicate
unhide pa
canned old
these are not
three separate devices
decision one divide
the
haifong
and day and
today at fort is going to reinvent the
phone
and here it is
d
actually areas but we're gonna leave it
there for now
before we get into it
let me ask
when we talk about a category of things
the most advanced phones are called
smart phones
so they say
and uh... they typically combine a fong
plus some
email capability plus they say it's the
internet for the baby internet
into one device in they all have these
plastic little keyboards on them
uh... and of the problem is
they're not so smart
and they're not so easy use so if you
can make a
no business school one oh one graph of
the smart access and uh...
easy z-axis
phones regular cell phones are kind of
like they're they're not so smart
and iron you know i'm not so easy views
uh...
but smart phones are definitely will
smarter but they actually are harder to
they're really complicated just for the
basic stuff people have a hard time
figuring out how to use them
well we don't want to buy the one of
these things
what we want to do is michael leapfrog
product
that is
what a smarter than any mobile devices
ever been
and super easy use
this is what i felt
we're going to reinvent the phone
now we're going to start
with a revolutionary user interface
the results of the years
of research and development
and of course it's an interplay of
hardware and software
why do we need a revolutionary user
interface i mean here's four smartphones
right motorola q blackberry
palm treo
nokia e sixty two the usual suspects
what's wrong with their user interface
as well
the problem with them
is really sort of in the bottom forty
there
it's it's this stuff right here
they all have these keyboards bitter
there whether you need them or not to be
there
and they all have these control buttons
vip are fixed in plastic
and are the same for every application
every application once a slightly
different user interface
a slightly optimize set of buttons
just for it
and what happens if you think the great
idea six months from now you can't run
around at a button to these things there
are any ship
so what do you do
it doesn't work
because the buttons and the controls can
change
the key a change for each application
making change
dan wrote if you think of another great
idea you want and for this product
well how do you solve this
it turns out we have solved that
we solve it in computers twenty years
ago
we solve it with a bitmap screen
the could displace anything we want put
any user interface up
and appointing device
we solve it with the mouse
we solve this problem so how are we
going to take this to a mobile device
what we're going to do
new is getting rid of all these buttons
and just make a giant screen
giants
how are we going to make it as we don't
carry around a mouse right
so what are we gonna do
a less violence right
where he is a stylist
now
now who wants a stylus
definitely around for a long way in the
wings and yes
nobody wants a styles
so let's not use the site
we're going to use the best pointing
device in the world where is the point
of ice they were all
warm with what's happened with news of
fingers
when the touch us with our fingers and
we have invented a new technology called
multi-touch
which is phenomenal
it works like magic
you don't need a stylus
it's far more accurate than any text
displayed its ever been shipped
ignores unintended touches it's super
smarts
multi finger gestures on it
and boy have we patented it
we've been very lucky
to abroad a few revolutionary user
interfaces to the market
in our time
first was the mouse
the second
was the click wheel
and now
we're gonna bring multi touch to the
market
and each of these revolutionaries around
faces
has made possible
a revolutionary product
the mac the ipod and now
the iphone
a revolutionary user interface we're
gonna build on top of that
with software now software on mobile
phones
like baby stuff
it's not so powerful
and today
we'll show you saw four breakthrough
software that's at least
five years ahead
of what's on any other phone
now how do we do this what we start
with a strong foundation
five phone runs all westinghouse
and
why would we want to run such as
sophisticated operating system
on a mobile device well because it's got
everything we need
it's got multitasking
it's got the best networking
it already knows how to power management
been doing this on mobile computers for
years
it's got boston security and the right
at
it's got everything from coco
and the graphics and it's got
quarantined built-in
and it's got the audio and video
that always tennis teams for it's gone
all the stuff we want
and it's built writing in so i found and
that has led us creates
desktop class
applications in networking
not the crippled stuff
that you find the most phones this
israel desktop class applications
one of the pioneers of our industry and
k has had a lot of great quotes
throughout the years
and i ran across one of them recently
that explains how we look at this
explains why we go about doing things
the way we do u cause we love software
and here's a quote
people who are really serious about
software
should make their own heart
callen says if it is
this is how you feel about it and so
were bringing breakthroughs software
to a mobile device for the first time
it's five years ahead of anything on any
of it from