this is a day
I've been looking forward to for two and
a half years
every once in a while
this is a day
this is a day I've been looking forward
to for two and a half years
every once in a while
a revolutionary product comes along that
changes everything and
Apple has been well first of all one's
very fortunate if you get to work on
just wannabes in your career Apple's
been very fortunate
it's been able to introduce a few with
these
into the world 1984
we introduced the macintosh then just
change Apple
change the whole computer industry %ah
in 2001
we introduced the first iPod and
if interest it didn't just change the
way we all this the music
it change the entire music industry well
today we're introducing
3 revolutionary products at this class
the first one is a widescreen iPod with
touch control by
the second is a revolutionary
the
and the third is a breakthrough
Internet communications device
no 3 thinks a wide screen iPod with
touch controls
a revolutionary mobile phone and a
breakthrough
Internet communications mice an iPod
of our own an Internet communicator
an iPod far
the K
these are not three separate devices
this is wonderful i the
and New York calling it iPhone
the
today
today Apple is going to reinvent
the farm and here it is
the
now
actually hear it is but we're gonna
leave it there for now so
before we get into it
let me are let me talk about a category
of things the most advanced phones are
called smart phones
so they say and
they typically combine a follow-on plus
some email capability
plus they say it's the internets for the
baby internet in the one device and they
all have these
plastic little keyboards on them I and
other problem is
that they're not so smart and they're
not so easy to use
so if you can make a you know business
school 101 graphic smart axis summer
easy to use Access phones regular cell
phones are kinda like they're they're
not so smart
9 a.m. you know not so easy to use I am
but smart phones are definitely will
smarter but they actually are harder to
use
they're really complicated just for the
basic stuff
people have a hard time figuring out how
to use them well we don't want to either
one of these things
what we want to do is make a leap frog
product
that is way smarter than any mobile
devices ever been
and super easy use vs is what I phones
cock we're going to reinvent the phone
now we're gonna start
with revolutionary user interface
is the result in the years
I've research and development and
of course it's an interplay of hardware
and software now
why do we need a revolution or user
interface I mean here's
for smartphones right Motorola Q the
BlackBerry
Pond Trail Nokia e62 the usual suspects
and what's wrong with their user
interface as well
the problem with them is really sort of
in the bottom forty there
its it's this stuff right here they all
have these keyboards
that are there whether you need them or
not to be there and they all have these
control buttons
that are fixed in plastic and are the
same for every application
every application wants a slightly
different user interface a slightly
optimize ceta buttons just for it and
what happens if you think a great idea
six months from now
you can't run around add a button to
these things are already shipped so what
do you do
it doesn't work because the buttons
and the controls can't change they can
change for each application
and they can change down the road if you
think another great idea you want to add
to this product
well how do you solve this hmm it turns
out
we have solved it we solved in computers
twenty years ago
we solved it with a bitmap screen the
cosplay anything we want
put any user interface up and a pointing
device
we solved it with the mouse right we
solve this problem so how we gonna take
this to a mobile device
what we're gonna do is get rid of all
these buttons
and just make a giant screen a giant
screen
now how are we going to communicate this
we don't carry around a mouse right
so what we gonna do our stylists right
we use a stylus now who wants a stylus
you have to get home and put them away
you lose 'em
yuck nobody wants a stylus so let's not
use a stylus
we're going to use the best pointing
device in the world where he's appointed
by Stu Worrall
born with one with Taliban when he's our
fingers
wanna touch us with our fingers and we
have invented
a new technology called multi-touch
which is phenomenal
it works like magic you don't need a
stylus
it's far more accurate than any touch
display that's ever been shipped
it ignores unintended touches it's super
smart
you can do multi finger gestures on it
and boy have we patented a
so
we've been very lucky to a broad a few
revolutionary user interfaces to the
market in our time
first was the mouse the second
was the click wheel and now
we're gonna bring multi-touch to the
market and each of these revolutionaries
are interfaces
has made possible a revolutionary
product
the Mac the iPod and now the iPhone
so a revolutionary user interface
we're gonna build on top of that with
software
now software on mobile phones is like
like baby soft for
it's not so powerful and today
we'll show you saw for breakthrough
software that's at least
five years ahead what's on any other
phone
now how do we do this while we start
with a strong foundation
iPhone runs OST the
now
why
why would we want to run such a
sophisticated operating system
on a mobile device while because it's
got everything we need
it's got multitasking it's got the best
networking
it already knows how to power management
doing this on mobile computers for years
it Scott awesome security and the right
aP's
it's got everything from Coco and the
graphics and it's got core animation
built-in
and it's got the audio and video the
West End is famous for it's got all the
stuff we want
and it's built riding in to iPhone and
that has let us create
desktop class applications and
networking
right not the crippled stuff
that you find on most phones this is
real desktop class
applications you know one of the
pioneers of our industry Alan K
has had a lot of great quotes throughout
the years and I ran across one of them
recently
that explains how we look at this
explains
why we go about doing things the way we
do because we love software
and here's the quote people who are
really serious about software
should make their own heart now Allen
said this thirty-year
and this is how we feel about so we're
bringing
breakthrough software to a mobile device
for the first time
it's five years ahead of anything on any
other phone
the second thing we're doing is we're
learning from the iPod
sinking with iTunes you know were gonna
shipper 100 millionth iPod this year
and thats all tens of millions of people
that know how to sync these devices with
their PCs or Macs
and sink all of their media right onto
the iPod
right see just drop your iPod in
and it automatically syncs you do the
same thing
with iPhone it automatically syncs to
your PC or Mac
right through iTunes and iTunes is gonna
sync all your media
on your iPhone your music audio books
podcasts movies TV shows
music videos but it also syncs but on a
date
you contact your calendars your photos
which you get on your iPod today
your notes you your bookmarks from your
web browser
your email accounts your whole email
setup all that stuff can be moved over
iPhone completely automatically
it's really not and do it he took like
two weeks
again go to iTunes and you set it up
just like you to set up an iPod or an
appletini and he set up what you want
sync to your iPhone
and it's just like an iPod charge
and sink so sync with iTunes third thing
i wanna talk about laws design we've
designed something wonderful
for your hand just wonderful this is
what it looks like
got three and a half inch screen on
it's really big and it's the highest
resolution screen with ever shipped its
a 160 pixels per inch
highest with ever shipped it gorgeous
and on the front
there's only one button down there we
call it the home button take you home
from wherever you are
that's it a cycle the side
it's really thin it's thinner than any
smartphone out there at 11 points six
millimeters
better than the Q there in the black
check for them all
it's really nice and we got some
controls on the side we got all switch
for remain silent we gotta
volume up and down control so the back
on the back the biggest thing I've
noticed we got two megapixel camera
built right in
the other side were back on the front so
let's take a look at talk now
we've got headset jack
three and a half a millimeter all your
iPod headphones fit right in
we've got a place at all tray for your
SIM card and we got one switch for sleep
and wake
just push it to go to sleep push its
wake up was likely the bottom
we've got a speaker got a microphone
and we got our 30-pin iPod connector
so that's the bottom now we've also got
some stuff you can't see
we've got three really advanced sensors
built into this phone
the first was a proximity sensor it
senses when physical objects get close
to you
bring iPhone apps you're here take a
phone call
it turns off the display and it turns
off the touch sensor instantly
what do you wanna do that want to save
battery but to see docket sprees inputs
from your face
in a touchscreen just automatically
turns what takeaway boots back on
so it's got a proximity sensor built ins
got ambient light sensor as well
we sense the ambient lighting conditions
and adjust the brightness of the display
to match the ambient lighting conditions
again
better user experience say its power and
the third thing we've got
is an accelerometer so we can tell when
you switch from portrait to landscape
it's pretty cool show it to you in a
minute so three advanced sensors built
in
sup let's go ahead and turn it on
this is the size of it it fits
beautifully in the palm of your hand
so an iPod phone
and internet communicate
let's start with the iPod
you can touch your music you could just
touch your music is so cool
widescreen video you can find your music
even faster gorgeous album art
on this display built in speaker
an why not cover for
first time ever on an iPod so around and
talk about this more
I'm a shorty
alrighty
now got some special
special iPhones up your legal special
born in a manner
so i get some digital video out I got a
little court here which goes up to these
projectors
and a so I got some great images
and you get see what it really looks
like so let me i've got a camera here
Singh see what I'm doing with my finger
for a few seconds
and I'll let me go ahead and get that
picture with a picture up I'm gonna go
ahead and
just pushed her sleep/wake button there
we are right there
and to unlock the phone I just take my
finger in sliding across
I macedonia conflict we wanted something
we could do by accident your pocket
to slide across boom and this is the
home screen
have iphone right here and so if I want
to get the iPod I just go down that
lower right hand corner in
push this icon right here emblem I'm in
the iPod
I wanna get home I push the home button
right here and I'm home
back in the iPod I'm back in the iPod
now here I am see five buttons cross the
bottom
playlist artists songs videos and more
I'm an artist right now how do I scroll
through my list of artists
I do this I just take my finger
and I school the
cool rubber banding up Mike
one of the edge the former pick somebody
will say wanna pick the Beatles I just
tap them and here's the Beatles songs
with their albums right here
wanna play sergeant Pepper's I just hit
sergeant Pepper's right there
and a will help from my friends was
gorgeous album artwork your
I got a boy control
not gonna love but not before now right
here you can see in the upper right hand
corner I could have gotten
foot the album art around has all the
other songs back here
likens play what we read if I want to
back around
very simple I could set some stars back
here just by
Sony rose after five
how cool
yeah for the night now
to show some self I just take my unit
here
and I China landscape mode I'll look
what happens
I'm Cover Flow the of Unadilla here
like a rolling stone
I just come through
come through my albums
really easy anytime I find some I like I
just turnaround play some
that easy
it's that simple not great now
alright I could play with this for a
long time
are now again I got play was here
I go to my playlist I got artists I got
songs
I got more over here I got you know
albums I got a great album view again
that shows all my album artwork right
here if I want are
and I've also got audio books and
compilations and things like that I've
also got videos here
I push videos and %uh i've got here I
got up I can be a podcast loaded on a
music video on
about TV show or movie might like to
show you the TV show here
this is an episode from the office all
videos we look at it nothing I am
BC presentation
okay
who are you faxing sorrow and mourning
I'll an hour
explain I don't have a ton of contact
with the screen
branch but before I left I'm took a box
white stationary
so from time to time I send why faxes
from himself from the future
what 8 a.m. today someone poisoned
the copy do not drink the coffee more
instructions will follow
quarterly future Dwight
a
create touch controls on here course not
awesome
an awesome what's going what now wanna
show you our a movie playing let's play
pirates of the caribbean: the second one
here
great movie by the way and a me
of now this is a wide-screen movie so I
just double tapping
see the whole thing here like got to
scream
job I like
and again I got on-screen controls was
in school freeway
movies just like this alrighty
so that is the iPod
pretty cool
we just started so again
touch your music scroll through song
school 3 playlists incredible widescreen
video
like you've never seen a portable device
160 pixels per inch
gorgeous screen quality gorgeous album
art
and Cover Flow best iPod we've ever made
can
some screenshots unbelievable
your son album art I just put up some
see what it looks like
just no matter what you like it looks
pretty doggone gorgeous
and of course Cover Flow and video
with on-screen controls
you know I was showing this to somebody
I was giving a demo to somebody a
little while ago who'd never seen this
before inside Apple
and I finished the demo said what do you
think he told me this
said he had school go
the iPhone with the most amazing iPod
ever
you can now touch music so that's the
iPod now
let's take a look revolutionary phone
we want to reinvent the phone now
what's the killer app the killer app is
making calls
it's amazing it's amazing
how hard it is to make calls on most
phones most people actually dial them
every time
most people don't have very many numbers
in their address book that use the
recent
as their address book right how do you
do that I bet more than a few
so we wanna let you use contacts like
never before
you can sync your iPhone with your PC or
Mac and bring down
all your contacts right in your phone
she got
everybody's numbers with you at all
times we have something
it's going to revolutionize voicemail
the day we call it Visual Voicemail
wouldn't it be great if you didn't if
you had six voicemails Indianapolis in
the five of them first before you want
it was in the sixth will not be great if
you have a random access voicemail
what we've got just like email you can
go directly to the voicemails it
interest you
x1 all the audio quality
iPhone is a quad-band GSM plus edge
phone
we have decided we decided to go
with the most popular international
standard which is GSM or on that
bandwagon
headed on that road map and now plan to
make a 3G phones and all sorts of other
amazing things in the future so
quad-band GSM plus edge and of course we
have wifi
and Bluetooth 2.0 with the art building
as well so this is what it looks like
when you get a call is what sounds like
it's one of our ringtones you can pick
up course
the so
I wanna show you four things I wanna
show you
the phone app photos
calendar and SMS
messaging the kind of things you would
find on a typical phone
very untypical way so let's go ahead
take a look so let's go to our phone
first you see that icon in the lower
left-hand corner the phone I just push
it right here
and bone I'm on the phone and I got five
buttons across the bomb
favorites recent contacts keypad and
voicemail I'm in contacts right now
again
how do I move around my contacts I just
scroll through
and so what's a I wanna make a call the
Johnny of
I'm just push here I see Johnny Ives
contacts
with alls informations three phone
numbers his email
whatever else his address whatever also
I've got it's all in one place
and if I wanna call Johnny all I do
is push his phone number Alcala's mobile
number right now
and now we are calling John here p turn
on speakerphone like this for 12
hey Johnny how you doing well it's been
two and a half years and I
I can't tell you how thrilled I am to
make the first public phone call
with iPhone by
I I remember when we first started
working on this and it's just
this just unbelievable what what what is
this I got another call coming in
johnnie can I put you on hold for a
minute
okay so I put johnnie on Holden
Highfill constant for the first call
I sorry phil as you can see it's put
it's for johnnie on hold and feel I can
just touch johnnie in
bring johnnie back a johnnie there it
was enough Ill call did you modify
conference in you can see the
the buttons change to merge calls right
there in the middle so I just push that
right here
and now I've created a conference call
by
johnnie their billionaire
of so here we are
and not what I gotta get back to my
keynote so what if I want to do that
when I just touch the Sarah right here
and
I'm gonna go ahead take Johnny private
here and put fill one hole johnnie
giving the say on the first phone call
for you
I it's not too shabby
you take care johnnie and I am this
calling it
bills on hola taken off a whole Phil
thanks very much I gotta get back to the
keynote now
I'll talk to you later i buy I alrighty
the
top
now I'm also got a way to make a list to
favorites here
from my most often called number so I
just touch it once and I'll
dial the number and I might want to add
somebody to favorites so let's say I
want to add Phil Schiller I just pushed
out plus button in the upper right hand
corner
right there and apart my favorites and I
can just go to
yes is here and there there's phil so
Phil Schiller right there and now all
put let's say I wanna put fills work
number
and it added Phil right there you can
see favorites
I can edit favorites by pushing the edit
button in the upper left hand corner
and I can move fill up if I want to you
know maybe the top
and what say I'm not gonna you know type
tony's changes number I gotta update
this anyways I'm gonna get rid of that
I can just remove Tony bomb there we got
that simple edit these things
very very easy I got recent right here
which is all my recent phone calls if I
wanna see the ones I've missed which
were in red I can just go up in
touch that button at the top and whom
those are all the ones I've missed
and those are all calls that I've placed
or have done if I wanna die on the phone
if I'm real last century
I can push keypad here and %uh i cant
I'll call just before
hoops called for sorry wrong number
up 408 a
man sex town soon other formats: the
numbers
and aFAIK want to I can I just keep
dying with its european number
I was just keep getting smaller real
simple very simple without the keypad
now let me show you Visual Voicemail
this is so cool
this is a collaboration we've done
which I'll talk more about later and
it allows us to have random access
voicemail go directly to the voicemails
we want so as an example I come to my
voicemail at all there's one by Al Gore
I want to hear that when I just push it
be there today
I'm hearing that training people to get
my flight show
but I want this day congratulations on
the iPhone
is unbelievably cool good luck with the
presentation
call me later now if I wanna call al
back right now its push the call back
button
but i wanna love someone from Tim Cook I
got here so it was with him the
care I've got ripple for one hour order
revenue while
be you know I'll just wait until your
again and is awesome
and so I've got voicemail how I wanna
listen to it when I wanna listen to it
any
order I wanna listen to it with Visual
Voicemail
so that is a quick tour up the phone app
now what I want to do is show you SMS
texting
so I just go to the S&S icon in the
upper left hand corner
and push it and I not only have SMS
texting
but I have multiple sessions so I can be
carrying on conversations with people
and every time I get a new message from
Mr be alerted to that might go check it
out so
as an example here I've got AQ and I've
been carrying on a conversation with any
and I just tap this in here's the
conversation I've been carrying on right
here
right and if there's a new message to
missus new message from Phil
and what see the conversation was what
hey Steve
hi still on for dinner tonight
absolutely your turn to pick
I think sushi Ron about seven o'clock
tonight and I said I can just say
you know sounds great I got the SEL
keyboard which is phenomenal it does
air for prevention and correction I'm
not that I'm
make some I probably will but it's
actually really fast the type of its
faster than always a plus the keyboards
and all the smartphones
so I can just say sounds great see you
there
unites Emma notice
right that simple
and I feel message me they are popular
doll see the dot I'm just go pick up the
conversation were left off if I wanna
send a message to any outdoor Scott I
just push this in
send a message and I'll it's so simple
so that's SMS messaging
and a you like again you've seen the
keyboard it's pretty awesome
we'll come back to that little bit later
and a third up I wanna show you as part
of the phone package
is photos you know we have a two
megapixel camera built-in as I said
we also have the course for management
app ever
certainly on a mobile device but I think
maybe ever and %uh so here's so here's
our photos I'm it on your photo library
and this is our library again I can just
scroll through photos here
with my finger precourt wanna go to our
photo album a pic
Italy and I just what's start at the top
and go through pictures I just swipe the
and a swipe through my phone or whatever
up there's one that's a its landscape I
can just turn my device in
take a look at pretty cool huh right
so I can even swipe 1 I'm in landscape
here you know was awesome
the other thing I can do is %uh I could
take any these pictures
and the I can make a bigger and %uh so
let me go ahead and get the camera back
up your there it is right there
I cannot I can just take my fingers and
i cant we call it the pitch
I can bring them closer together moving
further apart to make it bigger or
smaller
and so I can just move them further
apart and stretch your
him around
and now
now what I can do as I could have picked
you will make this my %ah wallpaper
and a course I could you know triggered
around them to set the wallpaper
and now 1i
if I'm back at home and I go to sleep
when I wake up from here on out
to life reset that's my wallpaper
whenever I make a call
that's what I'm gonna see bomb there we
go so photos
SMS an iPhone app that is part of our
phone package
for iPhone
call again
really great call management features
just scroll through contacts with your
finger
all the information at your fingertips
here
favorites last century
Visual Voicemail calendar
SMS texting incredible photo app
the ability just take any picture in
nature wallpaper
it's pretty unbelievable and I think
we have a chance to get your hands on
you agree we have reinvented the phone
okay well
now let's take a look and Internet
communications device
Sparta life so what's this all about
well we've got some real breakthroughs
here start off with
we've got rich HTML email on iphone
the first time really rich email on a
mobile device
and it works with any I'm ap or pop
email service
get your favorite mail service it will
likely work with
and its rich text email we
wanted the best web browser in the world
on her phone not a baby web browser a
web browser
are real web browser and we pick the
best one in the world Safari
and we have Safari running on iphone
it is the first fully usable HTML
browser
on a phone toward
we have Google Maps
map satellite images directions and
traffic
this is
on believable way to see it we have
widgets
starting off with weather in stocks and
was communicates with the Internet over
edge and WiFi
an iPhone automatically detects wifi and
switches seamlessly to it you don't have
to manage the network it just does the
right thing now
I'll take a second talk about email we
hook up to
almost any I map or pop 3 mail service
lets wanna give you some examples
I map of course is the best because you
keep your folders and all your email on
the server access it from anywhere
are Yahoo yahoo mail is I'm ap
Microsoft Exchange has an eye map option
and obviously dot Mac Mail as I map as
well pop 3
Google Gmail a while Malin most ISP's
a pop 3 email now I take a minute and
highlight
one yahoo mail yahoo mail
is the biggest mail service in the world
they have
over a quarter billion users
biggest email service in the world today
we are now meeting with Dr Who that they
are going to provide
free Porsche I'm ap email to all
iPhone customers so this is a test
i'm happy to mail it is Porsche I'm ap
email so you get a message
it will push it right out to the phone
for you same as a blackberry
free I'm at push email from ya week
that's a pretty big deal
so I'd like to do now as I'd like to
show you mail
Safari Google Maps
and widgets running on iphone
let's go see
so what's going to mail second icon from
left on the bottom there are just touch
it with my finger
and boom I'm there and so I got an inbox
here
and this is by the way running long live
on
ya who I'm ap email the stuff is coming
off a Yahoo server somewhere up in the
cloud
and the sewing say James Vincent here
sent me an email
he's proud father and there we go
and I'm to scroll here I got young wine
photos
rich text email there we go let's look
at another one
Phil Schiller she loved the gift again
in line photos rich text pretty nice
shopping list again rich text right here
pretty cool directions to sushi Ron for
tonight's dinner
now iPhone of course parcels out phone
numbers and as you can see there's a
phone number in blue
I could just touch it and boom I'm gonna
call this place
right I don't really wanna call us on
your in the call here
but you get the idea and now this last
one not
cam bresca as well whatever marketing
folks who just returned from an article
cans a great photographer and he took
all these great photos uva
have penguins in Antarctica will call
yes was great right in your Gmail
right on your phone and if I want to buy
the way
I can a look at my email with the split
view just like I do on my computer
and so I can select something here in
just look at it down here if I wanna
proves my messages real fast
just find that one message I was looking
for but I actually like the full screen
view
and of course we have a standard inbox
in traps in Satna
you know and all sorts of folders you
can put things in as well so it's real
email just like you're used to on your
computer right here
on your phone it's extraordinary and
again
free I'm ap email from Yahoo
now wanna go ahead just to create an
email message
show you what that's like so yeah when I
don't need the keyboard it's not there
when I do it's there I want to send a
message to
what's a film I just I P H and boom Phil
Schiller its address completion and
maybe I'll send one to Scott Forstall as
well
and their Scott right there and what's a
the subject is
dinner tenor
and a a you know whips
see you
tonight's
boom and I just sense and sends an email
when we're done
so that is male fall
just top-class email running on a mobile
device right now
I wish or something incredible on show
you Safari
running on a mobile device so let's go
to the web
and here we are I'm gonna load in around
an apple dot com here
little I morning universal site on a
load in the new york times its kinda
slow cycle has got a lot of images but
here we are loading we're loading over
wifi right now and
rather just give you a web version in
the New York Times
run and give you this rap version all
around we're showing you
the whole New York Times website near
this and guess what I can do I can
just put this in the landscape mode and
there it is right there
and I can scroll here if I want scroll
up and down here
from still loading in
we go or I can just get back like this
now
this is really great now I can see the
whole page but of course I can't read
it's all too small
so I get in with my fingers and pension
but we have an optimization I can just
double tap on anything in automatically
fills up the screen with and I can just
scroll around like this
school over here I can even make this
text bigger if I want to
and there it is
just double tap again to get back to the
four pages in school
and so I just with us there's the New
York Times
and again any article I want who here we
go
will
unbelievable now
you can look at mall tipple web pages as
well you have multiple web page is up so
I just push this button in the lower
right hand corner
transferred down and I can add a new
page if I want
and I'll go to war Amazon here at my
bookmarks
so let's go to Amazon I want to go to
the DVD section in the Amazon see what
DVD's are selling I like especially when
disney's are at the top
are and out so here's amazon.com even
for the whole pages load I'm just gonna
double tap on this and
and I'm so let's go to the DVD section
here
and now it's doing that
and here we are
and there's a section over here the
right hand side right there
and these are the top sellers updated
hourly a look houses inconvenient truth
is number one
right years of the governor's Grey's
Anatomy like that pirates of the
caribbean:
fantastic and so I've got this right
here and I can go back to the new york
times if I want
no assume up to the picture
we can all see it and again here the
school
over there about this one thank you
driven just by hitting the ex
and there we go in an incredible
Safari
no if you ever used what's called a web
browser on a mobile phone
you'll know how incredible this is I
hope you never really know
because it's it's bad out there today
and this is a revolution in the
first-order to really bring the real
internet to your phone let me show you
some about widgets here
all its gonna stocks right now on what
stock information of the web
and this right onto the phone here
all look apples are now
that's great
graph here for like two Yanda
that's fantastic with for the
percentages here all good
do it so I got stocks right here
and I can go look at the weather let's
see what what it's like outside
49 degrees
but supposed to get the 61 today so
that's good will to stay in here told
warms up now
I've got Paris right here I can have as
many these I want so it's night time in
Paris
it's actually warmer in Paris at night
than it is here today well
aspin no snow to later in the week
and Hawaii of its raining
that's not good well anyway here's four
places why aspin Paris
and San Francisco on again the weather
widget
now include
with the Internet device section here I
wanna show you something truly
remarkable
which is Google Maps on iphone
my hair Maps application here units
coming up
and shows us North America and I'm gonna
go to my Scotty west that's where we are
right now
and here we are who
that's where we are now what I'm gonna
do is I'm gonna go
I'll look for something I'm I'm gonna
certainly one cup coffee afterwards
so I'm just gonna look for Starbucks
right Starbucks on the search for
Starbucks
and sure enough there's always Starbucks
now
I'm gonna look at the Starbucks here
so I picked that one if I want and I can
even go look at that Starbucks
and there it is and was gonna call p p
good morning them how r have yes I'd
like to order four thousand what is to
go please
not just getting wrong number thank you
the
okay
now
I can zoom in up I just a again pinching
if I want to
or I can just double-click to zoom in
and I get just the higher and higher
resolution versions are the map
so let's go somewhere else here that
I've got bookmarked and
was gonna Washington Monument and so
here's Washington DC and I could do just
double Tappan
and I'm going in all further here just
double tapping in
and there's the Washington Monument
their or double-tap in again
and up but now I want to share something
else satellite images so I just had this
button called satellite down at the
bottom
and it's gone replaced the map a
satellite images there we go an hour
I'm just double tapia and double to
happen again
and no let's let's catch up to me here
there we go
and what double to happen again this is
the Washington Monument
there really is some people down
night forever well my phone
it's unbelievable so let's go I've got
another one at the Eiffel Tower which is
very cool
I set this one not to be a with there's
the Eiffel Tower
as people at the Eiffel Tower you can
see further
incredible and you're just one last one
have to show you the Coliseum in Rome so
again here we are
in Rome that's as far as we go with the
map we go further with the satellite
there's the Coliseum was the Roman
Coliseum satellite imagery
right on the phone wheeler that's the
Colisee
unbelievable right on turf
way go
so all these amazing things this is a
breakthrough
internet communicator built right in the
iPhone
the first rich HTML email on the phone
the first real web browser on the phone
best version of Google Maps on the
planet widgets
and all with edge in wifi networking
we're very very happy with this
again email push email
I'm ap free Yahoo and almost
any other I'm happen part mail service
you wanna hook up to
incredible
new technology for entering text far
better than we've seen on phones before
a real browser on the phone we can see
real web pages
in portrait or landscape we can zoom in
on what we
want to take a look at more closely
Google Maps
and widgets it's the Internet
in your pocket for the first time ever
now Ukiah you can't really think about
the Internet of course without thinking
about Google
right and for Google what we have on our
phone
working with them is a course Google
search we have that don't ride in the
browser
just type what you want had to go on
your of and Google Maps
with working very closely with them to
make this all happen
we're thrilled with the results and it's
my pleasure now
to introduce doctor Eric Schmidt
Google CEO